Guide to A. Michael Noll Papers RG.047
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
A. Michael Noll Papers
1960-2021
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
RG.047
10 Linear Feet
Biographical / Historical
A. Michael Noll was an early pioneer in digital computer art, 3D animation, and telecommunication in the 1960s and 1970s. He received his PhD in electrical engineering from the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn in 1971. He was employed by Bell Labs for nearly 15 years, working on basic research and beginning his focus in computer art and telecommunication. In the early 1970s, he was on the staff of the President's Science Advisor at the White House and later worked at AT&T, identifying opportunities for new products and services. He was a Senior Affiliated Research Fellow at the Columbia Institute for Tele-Information at Columbia University's Business School and was a member of the adjunct faculty of the Interactive Telecommunications Program at New York University's Tisch School of the Arts. He is a professor emeritus at the Annenberg School for Communication and Journalism at the University of Southern CaliforniaHe and served as interim dean of USC Annenberg from 1992 to 1994. He has published over ninety professional papers, was granted six patents for his inventions at Bell Labs, and is the author of twelve books on various aspects of communications.
Source: A. Michael Noll personal website, http://noll.uscannenberg.org/
Scope and Contents
The A. Michael Noll Papers contain documents from 1960 to 2021. These documents were assembled by Noll throughout his career and include many of the papers from his time at Bell Labs and AT&T. There are published works, digital art, research, and correspondence. All papers regarding Noll's Tactile Project are housed in this collection. The collection is 10 linear feet, located on bay 26, shelves 2C, 2D, 3D, 4D, and 3E of the Poly Archives.
Noll has donated related materials to other institutions as well. His computer art papers have gone to Rhode Island School of Design (RISD) Fleet. Computer art has gone to Los Angeles County Musuem of Art (LACMA). Some papers are housed at the Huntington Library in San Marino, California, and two large prints of his computer art are at the University of Southern California (USC) Fisher Museum. Some of his computer animation is at the Academy of Motion Pictures in Los Angeles and the Museum of Modern Art (MOMA) in New York. There is also a small collection at the Victoria and Albert Museum in London.
Arrangement
This collection comprises 7 boxes transferred from Columbia University and 7 boxes donated by A. Michael Noll. Original order was maintained when possible. However, during the accessioning process, the contents of the transferred and donated boxes were merged together into 10 boxes and arranged into these seven series:
Series I: Academia, 2004 Series II: Correspondence, 1986-2003 Series III: Digital Art, 1960-2016 Series IV: Photographs, undated Series V: Published Works, 1960-2021 Series VI: Research, 1961-2004 Series VII: Papers and Talks, 1967-2015.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Seven boxes were transferred to the Poly Archives from Columbia University in 2021. Additional boxes were donated to the Poly Archives by A. Michael Noll in 2021. Additional miscellaneous items were donated by A. Michael Noll in 2022. The accession number associated with this collection is 21-004.
Custodial History
The University Archivist at Columbia University (Jocelyn Wilk) contacted the Poly Archivist (Lindsay Anderberg) in November 2021 concerning a possible donation of A. Michael Noll's papers. Seven boxes of Noll's papers had been housed at the Columbia Business School with Professor of Finance, Dr. Eli Noam. As the Business School prepared for a move, they contacted Columbia Univeristy Archives about the collection. The collection was not a fit for Columbia, but seemed more appropriate for the Poly Archives, as Noll had recieved his PhD from Brooklyn Poly. The collection was described as "subject files on various telecommunication technologies that were emerging in the 1960s, 1970s and 1980s which ultimately became the ubiquitous technologies we are using today...It's a mix of reports, internal memos, publications and presentations. Very well organized by topic and in good condition. Among the technologies documented are "video text" "picture phone" and "CATV"." The Poly Archives accepted the donated and the transfer of the seven boxes occurred on December 7, 2021.
Following the transfer of the boxes from Columbia, Dr. Noll sent additional boxes of material from his personal collection to the Poly Archives in late 2021 and early 2022.
An accretion was added to the collection in 2025, a direct donation from Noll to the Poly Archives.
A second accretion in 2025 came from the Rhode Island School of Design (RISD). RISD maintained Noll's books from the orignal donation; the Poly Archives took on the manuscript collection of 2 banker's boxes (described in Series X: RISD 2025 Accretion.
Related Materials
NEW YORK/NEW JERSEY/NORTHEAST U.S.
Nokia Bell Labs Archives, Murray Hill, NJ Papers, books, films, and other materials relating to Noll's research at Bell Labs
New York Public Library A Computer-Generated Ballet [motion-picture] at NYPL's Performing Arts Library, Call number MGZHB 2-54 (original 16-mm print)
Museum of Modern Art, Department of Film & Video, New York City 16mm prints of computer animated movies, including Object W16896 "3D Movie (Head-to-Head) Random Object, Ballet, 4D Cube, Tetra, Sphere"
Fleet Library Rhode Island School of Design (RISD), Providence, RI Papers and books relating to Noll's computer art; 16mm computer animations
Michael & Anne Spalter, Private Collection Private collection of digital art, including Inventory ID: Noll-1963-01 and Inventory ID: Noll-1964-01
CALIFORNIA
The Huntington Library, San Marino, CA Michael Noll Papers, 1949-2016, The Huntington Library, San Marino, CA. Record number b1815342 Papers and books relating to computer art; videophone in 2001: A Space Odyssey).
Los Angeles County Museum of Art (LACMA), Los Angeles Michael Noll gift, accession numbers AC1998.105.1 to AC1998.105.87 Computer art prints, negatives, prints, papers
Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences Film Archives, Los Angeles 16mm prints of computer animated movies
USC Fischer Museum, Los Angeles Framed large prints of "Gaussian-Quadratic" and "Computer Composition" and reprints of published papers.
ENGLAND
Victoria & Albert Museum, London Gift of A. Michael Noll, accession numbers E.33-2011, E.34-2011, E.35-2011, E.36-2011 Published papers and photographic prints of computer art
ONLINE
Engineering Technology History Wiki (Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers) oral history, memoir, and writings including: A. Michael Noll Oral History, Interview #765, Conducted by Mary Ann Hellrigel and Michael Geselowitz, IEEE History Center, 10 May 2016 https://ethw.org/Oral-History:A._Michael_Noll
Archives: Memories - A Personal History of Bell Telephone Laboratories, 2015, https://ethw.org/Archives:Memories_-_A_Personal_History_of_Bell_Telephone_Laboratories
First-Hand:The Beginnings of Force-Feedback: A Memoir, Submitted by A. Michael Noll, February 4, 2022 https://ethw.org/First-Hand:The_Beginnings_of_Force-Feedback:_A_Memoir
First-Hand: Apollo 1 Disaster Tape Analysis by Bell Telephone Laboratories, Incorporated, Submitted by A. Michael Noll, September 11, 2015 https://ethw.org/First-Hand:Apollo_1_Disaster_Tape_Analysis_by_Bell_Telephone_Laboratories,_Incorporated
First-Hand: New Media at Bell Labs, submitted by A. Michael Noll, October 15, 2014 https://ethw.org/First-Hand:New_Media_at_Bell_Labs
First-Hand:Howard Wise Gallery Show of Digital Art and Patterns (1965): A 50th Anniversary Memoir, November 12, 2014, Published by A. Michael Noll in Leonardo https://ethw.org/First-Hand:Howard_Wise_Gallery_Show_of_Digital_Art_and_Patterns_(1965):_A_50th_Anniversary_Memoir
Telecommunication; Computer art; Computer science; Electrical engineering; Annenberg Center for Communication (University of Southern California)
- Series I: Academia, 2004
  - CITI Course Planning, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Library Display, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1986-2003
  - Sub-series A: General, 1986-2003
    - NSF Budget, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Einav, Gali-IPTV, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Sloan Goings On, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - John Redpath, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Eli Fundraising, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lenny Lakowsky, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Associate Director, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Sloan Grant, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - NIT Corporation Correspondence, 1996-2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Siemens Corporation Correspondence, 1986-1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Sloan, 1990-2003 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Letters, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sub-series B: Resumes and Proposals, 2000-2002
    - Forlano, Laura Sloan PH.D. 3-02, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Abraham, Reuben Developing Countries, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Ram Avrahami Information Costs, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Hakju Kim, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Kelly, John Sloan PHD Fellow, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Contracting + Foreign Investment Allison P. Fine, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Sonderegger, Petra PHD Proposal, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Paruchuri, Sri, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Nov 2002 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - NSF Disaster Recovery Grant 11/01, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Department Resumes, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Manral, Lalit Sloan PHD Fellow, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series III: Digital Art, 1960-2016
  Scope and Contents
  Noll devised and programmed computer animations during the early 1960s while he was employed at Bell Labs. The films in this series are examples of some of the earliest stereoscopic computer-animated films. This series contains a CD with digital versions of the films. These items were donated to the Poly Archives by Noll in 2021.
  - Digital Art 2016 CD, cuid3572 (Box 1, Item 1)
  - CD of Computer Animated Films, 2016; cuid3578 (Box 1, Item 2)
  - AMN Sequences (7 inch reel), 1960s; cuid3577 (Box 1, Item 3)
  - AMN 4D Sequences (5 inch reel), 1960s; cuid3576 (Box 1, Item 4)
  - Random Motion, Ballet head-to-head Stereo (5 inch reel), 1960s; cuid3574 (Box 1, Item 5)
  - 4D Hyper-Objects (5 inch reel), 1960s; cuid3575 (Box 1, Item 6)
  - Computer Ballet (3 1/2 inch reel), 1960s; cuid3573 (Box 1, Item 7)
  - Hyperobjects, 3D Adjacent (5 inch reel), 1960s; cuid3579 (Box 1, Item 8)
    16-mm print of Noll's computer animated stereoscopic movies of rotating four-dimensional Hyperobjects. Gifted by Noll to the Poly Archives in 2022.
    As described by Noll, "the film shows four-dimensional hyper-objects: a 4D hyper-cube with perspective and linear projection from 4D to 3D; a tetrahedron; and a 4D hyper-sphere with dots randomly scattered on its surface. The 3D stereoscopic projections are displayed on each frame with the left and right images adjacent to each other. I believe the left image is on the right of the frame, and the right image is on the left; so that when projected, they could be viewed cross-eyed."
    See relevant publication "Communications of the ACM vol.10 no. 8."
- Series IV: Photographs, 1964
  - Photographs of Vintage Computer Equipment, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Negative of a Drawing/Photo of the Tactile Device, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Gifted to the Poly Archives by Noll in February 2022.
  - 3D Stereoscopic Pairs - Originals, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series V: Published Works, 1960-2021
  - Sub-series A: Books, 1988-2018
    This sub-series contains books that were published or edited by A. Michael Noll with the exception of "Archaelologies of Touch" by David Parisi. This book was donated by Noll because it includes a chapter about "human-machine tactile communication" that describes Noll's Poly doctoral dissertation. To note, Parisi is a NYU History doctoral graduate.
    - Signals: The Science of Telecommunications by John R. Pierce and A. Michael Noll, 1990 (Box 1, Item 9)
    - Highway of Dreams: A Critical View Along the Information Superhighway by A. Michael Noll, 1997 (Box 1, Item 10)
    - Bell Labs Memoirs: Voices of Innovation edited by A. Michael Noll and Michael Geselowitz, 2011 (Box 1, Item 11)
    - Television Technology: Fundamentals and Future Prospects by A. Michael Noll, 1988 (Box 1, Item 12)
    - Introduction to Telephones and Telephone Systems Third Edition by A. Michael Noll, 1999 (Box 1, Item 13)
    - Archaeologies of Touch by David Parisi, 2018 (Box 1, Item 14)
    - Choosing Well: Finding the Best and Avoiding the Rest by Andrew Whaling and A. Michael Noll, 2010 (Box 2, Item 1)
    - Crisis Communications: Lessons from September 11 edited by A. Michael Noll, 2003 (Box 2, Item 2)
    - The Evolution of Media by A. Michael Noll, 2007 (Box 2, Item 3)
    - Introduction to Telecommunication Electronics Second Edition by A. Michael Noll, 1995 (Box 2, Item 4)
    - Principles of Modern Communications Technology by A. Michael Noll, 2001 (Box 2, Item 5)
  - Sub-series B: Digital Art, 1960-1969
    - Computer Animated Films Documentation, circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sub-series C: Opinion Articles, 1976-2021
    - Opinions, 1976-2021 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sub-series D: Scholarly Articles, 1961-2019
    - Professional Journals, 1961-2019 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Prometheus Volume 20 Number 3 September 2002, 2002-09 (Box 2, Item 6)
    - The End of an Era: A Memorial for AT&T, 2005-07-11 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Teleconferencing Articles and Research, 1975-2016 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Complete" Set '79, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - A. Michael Noll Published Papers, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Communications of the ACM vol.10 no. 8, 1967-08 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Feelie United States Original Patent, 1975-11-11-2022-02-06 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Contains the original of the patent granted to Bell Labs for Noll's tactile project, which was his Poly dissertation. Donated by Noll to the Poly Archives in 2022.
      According to Noll, Bell Labs gave the actual tactile device to Poly in the 1970s, but its current location is unknown. It would look like a metal cube with a plunger on its top.
    - 1969-1979 White Papers, Essays (Box 2, Item 7)
    - 1974-1984 at AT&T (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Feelies" Tactile PhD Dissertation and BTL Patent, 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Reprint from Computers and Automation: Stereographic Projections, 1965-05 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Sub-series E: Personal Articles, 2017
    - Edward E. David, Jr., 2017 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Sub-series F: Technical Memorandum, 1962-2021
    - Bell Labs Technical Memorandum (BTL TM), 2021-12-21 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Bell Labs Technical Memorandum, 1969-1976 (Box 3, Item 1)
    - Bell Labs Technical Memorandum, 1960-1968 (Box 3, Item 2)
    - Bell Labs Technical Memorandum August 28, 1962, 1962-2015 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Series VI: Research, 1961-2004
  - Sub-series A: General Research, 1961-2004
    - IFF Workshop, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Grapha Phone, 1975-1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - MOD-I, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Home Information Trial, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Slow Scan & Compressed Video, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - ISDN/ONA DSL, 1983-2000 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Satellites, 1981-2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Switching, 1961-1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Printers & Plotters, 1979-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Strategic, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Digital Radio, 1980-1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Signalling, 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - NSF-Background Info, 2001-10-30 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - The Future of Visual Information Systems (8-80), 1980 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Electronic Home-Information Systems Jan 8, 1981, 1981-01-08 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Computers and the Visual Arts, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Conc. Prop., 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Data Sharing, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - A History of Engineering and Science in the Bell System: The Early Years, 1975 (Box 4, Item 1)
    - 50 Years of A.R.R.L., 1981 (Box 4, Item 2)
    - A History of Engineering and Science in the Bell System: National Service in War and Peace, 1978 (Box 4, Item 3)
    - A History of Engineering and Science in the Bell System: Switching Technology, 1982 (Box 4, Item 4)
    - A History of Engineering and Science in the Bell System: Transmission Technology, 1985 (Box 4, Item 5)
    - Media History, 1984-1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Sub-series B: Audio, 1971-1993
    - Audio (recording, mikes), 1971-1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sub-series C: Fax, 1974-1993
    - Facsimile, 1974-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sub-series D: Fiber, 1976-1997
    - Local Loop (Fiber), 1978-1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Fiber Optics, 1976-1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - TAT-8, 1983-1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sub-series E: Networks, 1975-1997
    - Local Area Networks, 1975-1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Data Networks, 1978-1997 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Networks, 1984-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sub-series F: Picturephone, 1964-1994
    - Picturephone, 1969-1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Picturephone Research, 1973-1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Picturephone Studies, 1970-1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Bethany-Garfield AT&T, 1973-1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Picturephone, 1964-1975 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Sub-series G: Scholarly Articles, 2003
    - ITN Geneva, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Guide to the Case Law, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Sub-series H: Telecommunication, 1967-2013
    - Elisha Gray & The Telephone History, 1976-1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Tele-Writers, 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Foreign, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Teleconferencing, 1975-1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Spread Spectrum, 1982-1995 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Wireless (cellular, PCS, etc), 1982-1999 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Telephones, 1977-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - DMS, 1978-1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Transmission, 1967-1985 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 5ESS, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - ATM & Frame Relay, 1992-1998 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Telecommunications, 1980-1995 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Telecommunications Studies and Reports, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Teletext, 1972-1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - AT&T Originals (Selection), 1974-1982 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Integrated System, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Get-Set, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Interactive Graphical Communications Proposal (10-23-75), 1975-10-23 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Bell System, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Visual Communication, 1975-01 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - FirstWorld Communications Prospectus, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Remedies for Telecom Recovery, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Geodesic Network: 1987 Report on Competition in the Telephone Industry, 1987-01 (Box 7, Item 1)
    - Communications & Strategies: DigiWorld Economic Journal, 2013 (Box 7, Item 2)
    - Divestiture, 1976-1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Telecommunications Act of 1996 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Long Distance Rate Study, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - AT&T, 1974-1998 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Sub-series I: Television, 1967-2000
    - Television Stereophonic, Digital, 1982-1992 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Television International, 1967-1977 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Television General, 1986-1999 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Television Articles, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Television Theory, 1968-1997 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Television Cameras, 1982-1995 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Television Recording Technology, 1981-1992 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Television Display Technology, 1976-2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Television Use of VBI, 1988-1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - HDTV Facsimile Digital TV, 1976-2000 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - CATV Chairman Presentation, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Satellite TV, 1994-1998 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Television CATV, 1971-1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - The Effect of CATV Technology on the Bell System, 1979-04-09 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - The Wired Nation, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Multi-media Mania, 1991-1996 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Sub-series J: Video, 1974-2001
    - Video Telephone, 1977-1996 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Video Discs, 1974-1996 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Broadband, 1984-1999 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Interactive TV Superhighway Video Dial Tone, 1976-2001 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Sub-series K: Videotex, 1977-1989
    - Videotext Failure!, 1978-1989 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Videotex: Success or Failure?, 1977-1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Videotex Review, 1978-1983 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Sub-series L: Viewdata, 1978-1992
    - Viewdata, 1978-1992 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Standards (Viewdata, etc.), 1981-05 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Viewdata England, 1978-1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Viewdata Canada, 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Series VII: Papers and Talks, 1967-2015
  - Sub-series A: Annenberg Lecture Notes, 1967-2006
    - AT&T, 1979-2000 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 1986- Annenberg School Papers, Reports, Talks, 1986-1998 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Telecom Tech for Management, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Telecom Tech Education, 1992-2006 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - TV Technology, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The Effects of Divesture, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Perspectives on the Future of Telecommunication, 1987-1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Telecom Tech, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Perspectives on the Future of Telecommunication 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Lessons 1984-1997 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Basic Technology NYU-ITP Course, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Telecommunications Systems, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Engineering Concepts & Speech Signal Analysis, 1967-1984 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Sub-series B: Presentations, 1971-2015
    - Washington 1971-73 and Misc., 1971-2015 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Crisis! Citi Communications, 2002-2005 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Family Affairs Telecom, 1998-2002 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Sub-series C: Statements/Spoken Remarks, 2000
    - Hearing Telecom Subcommittee September 7, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Series VIII: Archived Website, 2022, May 2022; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Dr. A. Michael Noll's personal and professional website is hosted by the University of Southern California Annenberg School for Communication and Journalism. Dr. Noll is an emeritus professor of the Annenberg School and served as the interrm dean from 1992-1994. Dr. Noll's website includes biographical information, publication lists, and external links to examples of computer art and course syllabi. Dr. Noll continued to write and update his website after his retirement. At the time of the website capture in May 2022, the last update to the website was on October 9, 2019.
  Accruals
  Unless there are substantial updates to the website, this was a one-time capture.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
- Series IX: 2025 Accretion
  - AMN WOB DVD, 2025 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Nell's Bells A Radio History of Telephone DVD, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Reprints, 2014-2024 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Computer Composition With Lines, 1964; cuid3623 (Map-case Drawer 1)
  - Computer Composition With Lines (inverted), 1964; cuid3624 (Map-case Drawer 1)
- Series X: RISD 2025 Accretion